

PATRICK LIPPERT

Full Stack Developer

- Olympia, Washington 98502
- □ patrickdlippert@gmail.com
- (360) 686-2428

- in linkedin.com/in/patricklippert
- github.com/patrickdlippert
- # patricklippert.com

CAREER SUMMARY

Web Developer/Technical Director/Senior Technical Manager with experience in bringing large Enterprise Software systems to market. Strong organizational skills focused on Software Development Lifecycle principles, working inter-team (Development, Product Marketing, Quality Assurance and Operations) to achieve project goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

O Team Lead

Dick's Sporting Goods, Inc.

2019 - present

Team Lead for retail sales group. Responsible for business operations functions: electronic pricing, inventory adjustments, and signage programs.

Technologies used:



Andriod HTML/CSS

Owner/Entreprenuer

Knapp & Lippert Company

2005 - 2016

Ó

Owner/general partner in a start-up e-commerce and brick & mortar business. Created retail websites while developing key skills in product marketing, product selection, product research, business modeling. Responsible for employee recruitment and training using Learning Managment Systems (TalentLMS), design and all financial planning.

Technologies used:



LMS HTML/CSS JavaScript

Technical Consultant

Time Warner, Inc.

2010 - 2013

Consultant to Time Warner legal team to prepare documentation and technical review of AOL Engineering efforts for the Internal Revenue Service. Identified and presented evidence of capitalizable Research & Development work previously performed by teams at America Online.

Technologies used:







Full Stack Bootcamp

NuCamp Honors Graduate

Web Fundamentals **Bootcamp**

NuCamp

Frontend React/React Native

SKILLS & TOOLS

Angular JavaScript

Node.js

HTML/CSS/SASS/LESS

Backend

Express/MongoDB

PHP

Python/Django

Ruby/Rails Others

> DevOps Code Review

Git Unit Testing

Wireframing SDLC LMS

EDUCATION

Director of Engineering

America Online, Inc.

Department leader for the Engineering team responsible for AOL's Digital Imaging applications. Close interaction with company Business Development teams, Product Marketing, Operations and other technical teams during the product lifecycle. Also managed all third party technical teams, and evaluate opportunities for beneficial technical integrations.

Achievements

First use of a standardized enterprise platform at AOL (all server systems prior to it were built on in-house proprietary systems). Awarded several patents through development.

Technologies used:









Sr. Technical Manager

America Online, Inc.

2001 - 2002

Developed core infrastructure systems for AOL's "You've Got Pictures 2.0" digital imaging system. This was the first imaging system that was completely developed and hosted "inhouse." This included integration with several proprietary systems that involve authentication, member preferences, data mining, member notification. Job responsibilities included regular coordination with Product Marketing teams to develop requirements. Job also required coordination with Operations teams to roll-out and monitor these server systems. Responsible for a team of approximately 10 Software Engineers, most code developed for UNIX systems,

Technologies used:









MS in Electrical Engineering

University of Southern California 1990 - 1992

BS in Electrical Engineering

1985 - 1988

AWARDS

Patent: Monitoring **Digital Images**

Awarded US Patent #7,120,687, A technique for monitoring images from an online site, revewing and escalating for legal review.

Patent: Distributed **Image Storage** Architecture

Awarded US Patent #7,197,513. A file storage technique of generating "sparse" file directory structures and unique image IDs that refer to image file names.

INTERESTS

Hiking Home Improvement Guitar